<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>azure on 👨🏻‍💻 Michael John Peña ⚡️</title>
    <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/tags/azure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in azure on 👨🏻‍💻 Michael John Peña ⚡️</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>id</language>
    <managingEditor>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 02:19:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Hybrid Cloud Journey with Microsoft Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/hybrid-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 02:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/hybrid-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Hybrid cloud is the trend right now I see in a lot of companies and enterprises. The term hybrid has grown too in the last couple of years. It used to be just the connectivity between an on-premises data center to public clouds like AWS and Azure. This time, hybrid now also includes multi-cloud and edge computing. It&amp;rsquo;s about borderless connectivity across different topologies or deployment models happening around.
Why hybrid cloud?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI across the Microsoft Cloud</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/ai-across-the-microsoft-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 09:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/ai-across-the-microsoft-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Machine Learning (ML) are trending topics right now. In 2021, there are countless of ways to have a form of &amp;ldquo;AI&amp;rdquo; in your apps and platforms. A lot of companies from startups to software giants offer services that relate to this space. I spent the last 2 years exploring this space, and I still swimming my way as the movements in this area are quick and it&amp;rsquo;s hard to keep up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synology NAS Series – Cloud Sync with Azure Storage</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/synology-nas-series-cloud-sync-with-azure-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 03:55:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/synology-nas-series-cloud-sync-with-azure-storage/</guid>
      <description>Foreword Synology reached out to me to give their new DiskStation DS920+ a review. If you&amp;rsquo;re not yet aware of Synology, they are the leading NAS (Network-attached storage) provider for home and work use-cases. You can use a NAS for pretty much anything such as backing up files, sharing files in a local network, streaming media files, or have your own &amp;ldquo;private cloud&amp;rdquo;.
Throughout the years, the concept of NAS has developed and there is now a very thin line between doing things locally in your network and storage capabilities of cloud vendors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
