<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on 👨🏻‍💻 Michael John Peña ⚡️</title>
    <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on 👨🏻‍💻 Michael John Peña ⚡️</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>id</language>
    <managingEditor>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 02:19:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Andriel&#39;s Newsletter no. 17</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/andriel-newsletter17/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 02:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/andriel-newsletter17/</guid>
      <description>📰 What&amp;rsquo;s New? Therapy updates More 1 word sounds School updates Andriel’s birthday 🏫 Therapies and Schools Therapies 🎙 Speech Therapy 👋 We said goodbye to Bethany Price. Beth has been a big part of Andriel’s growth in the past 2 years. As we reflect on the past 2 years, Andriel have learned a lot of skills. From being non-verbal, poor receptive skills, and extreme lack of focus. Now Andriel can speak simple words (or at least will attempt), he has better awareness of things happening around him, and can now comply with simple instructions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andriel&#39;s Newsletter no. 16</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/andriel-newsletter16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 02:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/andriel-newsletter16/</guid>
      <description>📰 What&amp;rsquo;s New? 🗣 All time high in terms of communication metrics. 👋🏼 Goodbye Ben. 🪜 Continuous progress on all aspects. 🦷 Re-scheduled dental plans. 🏫 Therapies and Schools Therapies 🎙 Speech Therapy We’ve recorded an all time high in terms of Andriel’s use of main communication words: More, Help, and Yes. They are at a functional state at this point, that the words that he speaks mean the actual message.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andriel&#39;s Newsletter no. 15</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/andriel-newsletter15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 02:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/andriel-newsletter15/</guid>
      <description>📰 What&amp;rsquo;s New? 🗣 Reciting numerics and alphabets. 🚽 Toileting updates. 🚀 Continuous improvements. ☀️ A lot of fun outside! 🏫 Therapies and Schools Therapies 🎙 Speech Therapy Andriel is expanding his vocabulary. He is now getting trained on new words such as colours (yellow, red, blue) and animal names. Andriel continuously use verbal communications to request and ask for help. Andriel keeps hugging his mum and dad while saying “I yab you” (from ayayoo).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Andriel&#39;s Newsletter no. 14</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/andriel-newsletter14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 02:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/andriel-newsletter14/</guid>
      <description>📰 What&amp;rsquo;s New? 🤗 New therapists. 🏡 Moved to a new place. 🏫 Busy with finding schools. 🚽 Toileting updates. 🗣 Speaking a lot of 1 word-ers. 🏫 Therapies and Schools Therapies 🎙 Speech Therapy Andriel is now back on track in terms of his engagement and focus when doing therapies. Andriel is almost accurate with his &amp;ldquo;Yeah&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Nah&amp;rdquo; where they are more in context and appropriate. Beth and the family have worked on turn taking and it&amp;rsquo;s showing progress as Andriel learns to wait.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run for Autism - 2021</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/run-for-autism-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 02:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/run-for-autism-2021/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago, I started a campaign to raise money into my Run For Autism 2021. Long story short, I made it! Raising the money, running the distance, and raising more awareness. It&amp;rsquo;s been a challenging journey given I experienced a lot of adversaries along the way.
Here are some of the key takeaways of this journey: - Always define the purpose - Set realistic expectations - Love the process - Deliver what you&amp;rsquo;ve committed - Know when to rest</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Productive this Pandemic - Accountability Partner</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/accountability-partner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 02:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/accountability-partner/</guid>
      <description>For the longest of time, I would consider myself as the lone wolf at work. Most days, I&amp;rsquo;d rather stay alone and be in my world to get things done. I found in the past that the effort to collaborate is counterintuitive and would just mean more work for me. Back then, I&amp;rsquo;d rather do things &amp;ldquo;my way&amp;rdquo; than to delegate so that I don&amp;rsquo;t get disappointed with the results from someone else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Productive this Pandemic - Planning your week ahead</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/planning-your-week-ahead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 02:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/planning-your-week-ahead/</guid>
      <description>People have asked me lately, how do I do it? Having a full-time consulting company, spending quality time with family, doing groceries, cooking, house errands, taking part at online communities, blogging, journaling, building a house, getting involved to a dozen startups, creating a podcast, reading books, losing weight, and the list goes on.
It&amp;rsquo;s even harder because it&amp;rsquo;s the pandemic. Most people&amp;rsquo;s motivation and morale are down right now because of the never ending lockdowns, non-purposeful workplace, fear of missing out, and other negative emotions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hybrid Cloud Journey with Microsoft Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/hybrid-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 02:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/hybrid-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Hybrid cloud is the trend right now I see in a lot of companies and enterprises. The term hybrid has grown too in the last couple of years. It used to be just the connectivity between an on-premises data center to public clouds like AWS and Azure. This time, hybrid now also includes multi-cloud and edge computing. It&amp;rsquo;s about borderless connectivity across different topologies or deployment models happening around.
Why hybrid cloud?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using WSL2 (Windows Subsystem for Linux) for Blockchain Development</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/blockchain-wsl2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 02:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/blockchain-wsl2/</guid>
      <description>In the past, I&amp;rsquo;ve been using my Macbook Pro to do all things blockchain and smart contracts development. One of the hurdles I encountered in the past is that some tooling and frameworks were not first class citizens on Windows. Majority of these tools, especially those that come with scripts and complex networking architecture (circa 2015) just works in MacOS and Linux:Ubuntu.
Introduction Of course there have been a lot of improvements now in the ecosystem since then.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are these blockchain and crypto tokens?</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/blockchain-tokens/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 02:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/blockchain-tokens/</guid>
      <description>So you keep hearing or reading about &amp;ldquo;tokens&amp;rdquo;, these &amp;ldquo;cryptos&amp;rdquo;, the &amp;ldquo;blockchain bitcoins&amp;rdquo;, and so on. It&amp;rsquo;s been quite some time now that it has involved me with blockchains and cryptos that over and over, I have to explain to people (often new clients) on what are these tokens. Even until now, at almost late 2021, I still get asked about these: Is it Bitcoin? Is it Ethereum? Is it Coin X, Coin Y?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing MacOS Apps using .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/developing-macos-apps-using-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 02:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/developing-macos-apps-using-net/</guid>
      <description>The .NET framework (and the wider ecosystem) has embraced a lot of openness these past few years. Gone are the days when .NET only works on Windows. However, as the journey to &amp;ldquo;One .NET&amp;rdquo; is still unfolding, there is a lot of confusion on how we can use .NET on MacOS. There is Mono, .NET Core, .NET 5, Xamarin.Mac, Xamarin.Forms, Mac Catalyst, .NET 6, and MAUI. This blog post explains some of the core concepts across these nomenclature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Message to the young</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/message-to-the-young/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 16:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/message-to-the-young/</guid>
      <description>I recently gave a graduation speech to my high school alma matter. Compared to my usual technical talks, this time it&amp;rsquo;s about inspiring the younger generation and to share some of the key lessons and experiences I&amp;rsquo;ve had for over 12 years since I graduated. This is also a good reflection of what I will advise my younger self if I am talking to him right now.
Below, I summarize my speech that is in a written medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with DeFi</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/getting-started-with-defi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 16:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/getting-started-with-defi/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Blockchain is not dead. Actually, quite the contrary is happening in the past year. There are more and more interest and it&amp;rsquo;s gaining a lot more traction than before. A big portion of this growth is due to &amp;ldquo;DeFi&amp;rdquo; AKA Decentralised Finance applications. From the hyped cryptocurrencies, we are now seeing the new next wave of this transformation as we see more financial products being developed: lending, exchanges, yield farming, and pools just to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Ultimate Windows and Mac Setup (2021 Edition)</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/my-ultimate-windows-and-mac-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 16:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/my-ultimate-windows-and-mac-setup/</guid>
      <description>Introduction My Battle Station @ 2021
In a parallel world, I&amp;rsquo;ll be just using 1 device and 1 Operating system for all the things. However, given the nature of my work with mobile, web, blockchain, machine learning, and cloud development, I need to have multiple devices to cater things.
I tried doing &amp;ldquo;Shared mouse and keyboard&amp;rdquo; in the past such as Synergy, but I decided to use a KVM switch instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH Connect to Linux Server from a Mac using SOCKS5 Proxy</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/ssh-connect-to-linux-server-from-a-mac-using-socks5-proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 16:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/ssh-connect-to-linux-server-from-a-mac-using-socks5-proxy/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending a lot of time lately in setting up on-premises Linux Servers. There are a lot of reasons why you would like to SSH to a Linux server such as checking configuration files, copying files, or even port forwarding.
Just open your MacOS terminal and the command to ssh to a Linux Server is as simple as:
ssh user@host or ssh michael@192.0.0.1
However, where it gets tricky is when you need to use a proxy such as SOCKS5 in order to access that Linux server from your MacOS machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to disable auto-locking of MacOS Keychains</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/how-to-disable-auto-locking-of-macos-keychains/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 23:27:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/how-to-disable-auto-locking-of-macos-keychains/</guid>
      <description>Signing an iOS app for release is one of the trivial things most mobile developers face. A lot of CLIs and SAAS emerged as part of this struggle. However, not all companies have adopted to those tools and they still prefer to build their apps in their on-prem data servers. They use something like TeamCity or Azure DevOps Server.
We streamlined the configuration of our Mac Build agents to a repository where we can update our Provisioning Profiles, Keychains, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 3 Types of Blockchain and Cryptocurrencies people I’ve met</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/the-3-types-of-blockchain-and-cryptocurrencies-people-ive-met/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 03:28:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/the-3-types-of-blockchain-and-cryptocurrencies-people-ive-met/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been in the crazy Blockchain space for quite a while now. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of conversations and people I&amp;rsquo;ve met online and in-person to talk about it. Over and over, I see patterns on the people I interact with whether they do it as part of their job, an enthusiast, developer, investor, or simply just a person.
I&amp;rsquo;ve probably had hundreds of interactions already and most likely, they will belong to either of these 3 buckets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I don’t read or watch mainstream media that much</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/why-i-dont-read-or-watch-mainstream-media-that-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 05:45:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/why-i-dont-read-or-watch-mainstream-media-that-much/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I was a kid, I was never really the person who watches the mainstream television to watch news. Watching news on a television is a culture that a lot of people just grew up with as a &amp;ldquo;default.&amp;rdquo;
Here are some of thoughts on why I don&amp;rsquo;t value reading or watching mainstream media anymore.
The important news will come to you one way or the other. They are written or crafted to trigger emotions rather than inform about things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why you should experience being self-employed</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/why-you-should-experience-being-self-employed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 21:18:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/why-you-should-experience-being-self-employed/</guid>
      <description>In someone&amp;rsquo;s employment life, she/he dreams of having her/his own company to beat the thoughts of having a manager or a boss. You know the promise of being your own boss, handling your own time, and $$$ - who wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want that? It&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;relatively&amp;rdquo; easy to establish a company compare to the last decades - thanks to technology. There are also a lot of avenues to profit from &amp;ldquo;the gig economy&amp;rdquo; that sometimes get big and would need a team to work on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to beat procrastination</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/how-to-beat-procrastination/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/how-to-beat-procrastination/</guid>
      <description>One of the colossal beasts that all knowledge workers fight time and time again is procrastination. This is when you know you should work, but you don&amp;rsquo;t have enough willpower to do it. You can&amp;rsquo;t code, you can&amp;rsquo;t do that design document, you can&amp;rsquo;t write that next blog post&amp;hellip; the list goes on. Here are 5 of my usual methods when I&amp;rsquo;m stuck in that limbo.
Avoid Distractions The first and obvious thing that you have to do is to avoid distraction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You should read books, you know you should</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/you-should-read-books-you-know-you-should/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 20:47:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/you-should-read-books-you-know-you-should/</guid>
      <description>Before 2018, I was never a book reader. Reading a book seems like a chore to me. I can barely finish a chapter. I always had that internal conflict (possibly based from childhood experience) that only &amp;ldquo;the smart people&amp;rdquo; can read books. Another factor is, I&amp;rsquo;ve always associated books to &amp;ldquo;school&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;academia&amp;rdquo; that felt like an enclosed culture that didn&amp;rsquo;t really synced in to me. Also, I&amp;rsquo;d rather watch a film or TV series than read a 300 to 500 pager book - because of cinematics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI across the Microsoft Cloud</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/ai-across-the-microsoft-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 09:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/ai-across-the-microsoft-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Machine Learning (ML) are trending topics right now. In 2021, there are countless of ways to have a form of &amp;ldquo;AI&amp;rdquo; in your apps and platforms. A lot of companies from startups to software giants offer services that relate to this space. I spent the last 2 years exploring this space, and I still swimming my way as the movements in this area are quick and it&amp;rsquo;s hard to keep up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why it’s okay to be “an ordinary” developer</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/why-its-okay-to-be-an-ordinary-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 19:22:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/why-its-okay-to-be-an-ordinary-developer/</guid>
      <description>Someone once asked me, what does it take to become a prominent developer? A 10X Engineer? You know some who are &amp;ldquo;extraordinary&amp;rdquo;. What do you mean by extraordinary? I&amp;rsquo;ve always had some thoughts (all of us do) around it, but my understanding and opinion of it is now much more concrete. Actually, this applies not only to being a developer, but to any other career or profession that you&amp;rsquo;re in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Intentionalization: Don’t click that next button</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/digital-intentionalization-dont-click-that-next-button/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 22:29:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/digital-intentionalization-dont-click-that-next-button/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s very tempting to click on &amp;ldquo;that next button&amp;rdquo; wether that is from YouTube, Netflix, Facebook videos or any endless buffet of consumption. You start watching a video about a topic you&amp;rsquo;re really interested in to and end up watching something weird after 3 hours. As I do more research in my personal journey of Digital Intentionalization, this is probably one of the most obvious ones. We let the platform play the next content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My only goal for 2021: Digital Intentionality</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/my-only-goal-for-2021-digital-intentionality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 23:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/my-only-goal-for-2021-digital-intentionality/</guid>
      <description>During the holidays, I was contemplating on what skills should I invest time on for 2021. As someone who is working in the technology field, there are a lot of exciting things to double-down on: from Artificial Intelligence (AI), Internet of Things (IoT), Blockchain, and a plethora of technology trends. As I reflected on how my 2020 went in terms of career and lifestyle, I noticed that there is an area I really need to work on - my digital life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synology NAS Series – Cloud Sync with Azure Storage</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/synology-nas-series-cloud-sync-with-azure-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 03:55:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/synology-nas-series-cloud-sync-with-azure-storage/</guid>
      <description>Foreword Synology reached out to me to give their new DiskStation DS920+ a review. If you&amp;rsquo;re not yet aware of Synology, they are the leading NAS (Network-attached storage) provider for home and work use-cases. You can use a NAS for pretty much anything such as backing up files, sharing files in a local network, streaming media files, or have your own &amp;ldquo;private cloud&amp;rdquo;.
Throughout the years, the concept of NAS has developed and there is now a very thin line between doing things locally in your network and storage capabilities of cloud vendors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Years of being a Microsoft MVP!</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/5-years-of-being-a-microsoft-mvp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 07:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/5-years-of-being-a-microsoft-mvp/</guid>
      <description>Wow! It’s been 5 years since my first Microsoft MVP award. If you don’t know what the Microsoft MVP program is, check this site. Throughout the years, I have transitioned from various categories and technology award. In particular, Windows Development (Windows 8/8.1/10/RT and XAML), to Developer Technologies (C#, .NET, Xamarin), to Azure with focus on Blockchain, PAAS (Platform as a Service), and Integrations.
In those years, I’ve seen Microsoft and the MVP program changed a lot (for the better).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I’m going to start writing again!</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/writing-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 07:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/writing-again/</guid>
      <description>I have been meaning to write a blog post for an awfully long time, but it has blocked me for so many reasons. There are many reasons I stopped writing. I find different excuses for not doing it. Lazy. Busy. Afraid that contents I write may not be good enough. I feel my English is not good enough. So much more. No one will read it, why write?
But then the more I think about it, the more I realised that I spend a lot of time in my day writing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
