<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Statuses on 👨🏻‍💻 Michael John Peña ⚡️</title>
    <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Statuses on 👨🏻‍💻 Michael John Peña ⚡️</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>id</language>
    <managingEditor>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 03:56:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Time is scarce</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-25-time-is-scarce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-25-time-is-scarce/</guid>
      <description>The most scarce resource is your time and attention. Specially if you live and breathe “tech”, it’s very easy to get sidetracked and distracted. Often, we forget what really matters and what really brings a purposeful life to us. The best thing that you can give to support someone is your genuine, undivided attention. Experiencing the actual connection with someone is the reward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everyone is unique</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-24-uniqueness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-24-uniqueness/</guid>
      <description>We should celebrate everyone’s uniqueness but also understanding that we’re also not so different from each other. I’ve learned to think less of myself and really try to listen and be more effortful in understanding other people’s point of view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work is just work</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-23-work-is-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-23-work-is-work/</guid>
      <description>Work is just work. Business is just a series of transactions, numbers, and deliverables. Money is just an instrument. They all come and go. You can always have more if you spend more time and resources on it. I realized I don’t want to spend 100+ hours a week on work-related activities, while being blindsided thinking it’s for the best of “my family” where, in fact, I’m just serving myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birthday</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-22-go-to-europe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-22-go-to-europe/</guid>
      <description>I want to someday go to Europe and explore the rich history of the world. It&amp;rsquo;s very unlikely that I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to go to all 7 continents of the world, that&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;m at least just aiming 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birthday</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-21-birthday/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-21-birthday/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s my birthday. Although I don&amp;rsquo;t really believe in &amp;ldquo;just wishing&amp;rdquo; without really putting the action and effort to it, it&amp;rsquo;s still a good reminder on what do you want at that specific moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I missed taking flights</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-20-taking-flights/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-20-taking-flights/</guid>
      <description>Gosh, I really missed the joy of taking flights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing a non-fiction</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-19-non-fiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-19-non-fiction/</guid>
      <description>I want to publish a non-fiction book someday. I&amp;rsquo;m not yet sure about the content, but it&amp;rsquo;s something that I want to do. Why do I want it? Because I want to share a lot of my knowledge, wisdom, and passion to a lot of people. In the process, I would also like to help some people unlock their best potential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain craze</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-18-blockchain-craze/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-18-blockchain-craze/</guid>
      <description>There is no stopping in this Blockchain craze. From cryptocurrencies, DeFi, NFTs, and now the Metaverses. It&amp;rsquo;s going to be an interesting next few years in this space and industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideal job</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-17-ideal-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-17-ideal-job/</guid>
      <description>The ideal job exists. It&amp;rsquo;s not perfect, but ideal. It&amp;rsquo;s when you&amp;rsquo;re both learning and earning, and at the same time pursuing an interest. You should be learning, as the world changes, you&amp;rsquo;re also adopting to the global trends. In a fulfilling career, making money is often a bonus or a vehicle to keep going. Often the ideal jobs are when you&amp;rsquo;re enjoying the process and the daily grind of it, rather than just working on it for renumeration purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enjoy the little things</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-16-little-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-16-little-things/</guid>
      <description>Enjoy the little things. When we&amp;rsquo;re working towards a huge and ambitious goal, we tend to be anxious about how we can get there. We then forget that it&amp;rsquo;s actually a long journey, and you have to stop and rest once in a while. As part of this rest, you should also enjoy the simplest events in your life.
So what are these little things? Your child asking you to go for a play.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hairstyle</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-15-hairstyle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-15-hairstyle/</guid>
      <description>This past few months with the pandemic and lockdown, I haven&amp;rsquo;t had a good chance of fixing my hairstyle. I stopped caring about it couple of years ago. From what people have told me, I look best and presentable when I have a shorter hair.
However there is a bigger symbolic reference of haircut on my end. It&amp;rsquo;s about taking off some of the accumulated baggages that I had for the past few months in order to take more load eventually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking naps</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-14-taking-naps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-14-taking-naps/</guid>
      <description>Taking a nap is something I often forget these past few months because of working from home. I am a serial napper. I am notorious to take a nap anywhere. Even on 5 to 10 minute bus rides, I can still take a micro nap.
This is one of the reasons why I am so energetic both at work and at home before pandemic. I use the pocket of times to either do something that interests me or take this time for a nap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love is effortful</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-13-love-is-effortful/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-13-love-is-effortful/</guid>
      <description>Love is effortful and attentive. It&amp;rsquo;s a good disturbance in our lives. It is a continuous process that we develop on a daily basis. It&amp;rsquo;s about giving the best quality time despite having limited free time because of all the work and ventures that you&amp;rsquo;re doing. It&amp;rsquo;s about the constant reminder of what really matters.
You don&amp;rsquo;t just say you love someone (or something) without putting the attention and effort on making it better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being different to be sucessful</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-12-being-different-successful/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-12-being-different-successful/</guid>
      <description>In order to be successful, you have to do things differently from others. The key words are &amp;ldquo;do&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;different&amp;rdquo;; and both of them needs to be present. It&amp;rsquo;s not enough to just &amp;ldquo;be different&amp;rdquo; - like you&amp;rsquo;re different from others because of your background, personality, or skills. It&amp;rsquo;s about applying actions on those different ideas. It&amp;rsquo;s about trying to think outside the box, but also working on testing if the idea is viable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Political Season</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-11-political-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-11-political-season/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s the political season again in the Philippines and my whole network back there are all over places expressing their opinions and political views. At this point, I don&amp;rsquo;t really have much to say about it, and I don&amp;rsquo;t have the right mindset and priorities to be in it. I have other set of problems and deliverables to deal with. I have business ventures to run, and ideas that needs to be polished, tested, and executed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investing</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-10-investing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-10-investing/</guid>
      <description>Investing is better than saving. But saving is way better than spending so much. Investing is a means of earning more money by using your existing money as an instrument. Again, money begets money.
My general rule in life is that whatever it takes, yield at least 6% more each year. This is just a guidance that you should earn at least 6% more to beat the inflation. Your money, if just sitting on the bank, will depreciate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking of topics</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-09-thinking-of-topics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-09-thinking-of-topics/</guid>
      <description>There are so many topics you can talk about in life. There are things that are easily relatable to your actual experience, then there are those that are more abstract, some are just really so random.
Whatever you&amp;rsquo;re writing or researching, you just have to define who is it for? Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s for you, maybe it&amp;rsquo;s for someone else, or maybe no one really has to know. The audience is really for you to work on later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How much is your time?</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-08-how-much-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-08-how-much-time/</guid>
      <description>How much is your time? That is the question you should always ask yourself. Over and over again, we have to know that the most valuable resource in this planet is your time and attention. It&amp;rsquo;s not just about the title or the money that you have, although they can be really useful instruments for your means but it&amp;rsquo;s not the ultimate resource.
The whole purpose of life is to find ways to actually make good use of those time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autopilot</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-07-autopilot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-07-autopilot/</guid>
      <description>Never go to autopilot. This is a state when you&amp;rsquo;re just trying to live the day, expecting a better tomorrow. I have to keep reminding myself from time to time if what I&amp;rsquo;m doing is something that is within my ideals and interests, or I&amp;rsquo;m just riding someone&amp;rsquo;s (or something) wave. This is a life-long struggle as we know more about ourselves and what our &amp;ldquo;purpose&amp;rdquo; is.
I know it&amp;rsquo;s hard because there are some aspects of your life, like chores and work meetings, to be just &amp;ldquo;BAU&amp;rdquo; or business as usual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep Producing</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-06-keep-producing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-06-keep-producing/</guid>
      <description>Keep producing no matter how hard it gets. As a creative worker who is a programmer &amp;amp; software architect, a business owner, a startup advisor, a writer, an amateur content creator, and a lot more; they all revolve in the digital realm of &amp;ldquo;you must produce something.&amp;rdquo;
One thing I make sure I do everyday is I journal all my thoughts and significant events throughout the day. I always make sure I write for at least 15 minutes, every single day - even if I&amp;rsquo;m not in the mood or it&amp;rsquo;s a terrible day at work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ideas are cheap</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-05-ideas-cheap/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-05-ideas-cheap/</guid>
      <description>Ideas are cheap. As a noun, it means nothing but a reference to something that could be great. It&amp;rsquo;s just an abstract concept that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any tangible way for either you or others to experience.
In order for ideas to mean something, it needs to transition from a noun to a verb (action) because by only putting the work and process on to it, that&amp;rsquo;s when value comes in. Only then, the idea becomes a product, a service, an outcome - and eventually turn in to business, profit, and purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money is just an instrument</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-04-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-04-money/</guid>
      <description>Money is just an instrument. It&amp;rsquo;s a means to get or achieve something. It&amp;rsquo;s not the reason to live nor should be the cause of break-ups and damaging relationships. We all need money in order to at least get the minimum requirements to live: shelter, food, health, and safety. Anything beyond that is on the &amp;ldquo;wants&amp;rdquo; and it&amp;rsquo;s subjective person to person.
I am at peace of the money that I have and the money that I will own in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NFT Hype</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-03-nft-hype/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-03-nft-hype/</guid>
      <description>There is so much happening in the NFT space right now, it&amp;rsquo;s so interesting, fascinating, and intimidating at the same time. While most of my circles are still stuck in to the enterprise applications and the more traditional web &amp;amp; mobile applications, a select people are changing the world by storm. There is a little fear of missing out on my end, but for me that&amp;rsquo;s really adding some spice to this universe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newsletter</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-02-newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-02-newsletter/</guid>
      <description>Newsletters are fun. It&amp;rsquo;s a way to consume information that are specific for an audience. I actually subscribe to a bunch of them. It&amp;rsquo;s my way of getting updated on a topic that interests me, but at the same time, still curated and fact-checked by someone smarter than me in that field.
In the increasingly connected world of social media, we tend to find content that are more fitted to our needs and interests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetings - Productivity Killers</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-01-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-10-01-meetings/</guid>
      <description>Meetings are one of the killers of productivity. Specially if you have other functions or roles beside attending and organizing meetings. For example, if you&amp;rsquo;re also a developer or a knowledge person who needs enough focus to get on with a productive and meaningful outcome.
Some meetings are really ideal when there are so many unknowns and we want to collaborate and just get on with it, instead of bouncing on/off with emails and chat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Trolls</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-30-trolls/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-30-trolls/</guid>
      <description>Trolls are people on the internet who have the intention of getting in to your nerves by distracting you with bashful or hurtful comments. They are masked with a fake account and doesn&amp;rsquo;t really show who they are and how they are related to you. Some of them are just completely random, some of them are targeted from your peers and network.
The moment you entertain them, then they become successful on what they intended to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serial Achiever</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-29-serial-achiever/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-29-serial-achiever/</guid>
      <description>The best advice you can give to someone (or even yourself) is &amp;ldquo;to become a serial achiever.&amp;rdquo; Not &amp;ldquo;to be rich&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;to be successful&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;to be the best X professional&amp;rdquo;. Most of these are too vague, too shallow, too specific, and most of the time not relatable and practical for the rest of 99% population. Also, continuity is important as this brings you on to &amp;ldquo;what&amp;rsquo;s next&amp;rdquo; after reaching a specific outcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vertical Monitors</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-28-vertical-monitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-28-vertical-monitor/</guid>
      <description>I never really understood why I wanted a vertically mounted monitor. I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s cool and &amp;ldquo;different&amp;rdquo; but I still haven&amp;rsquo;t seen the real use case of it. I think the whole idea is for it to be just open on the side and it&amp;rsquo;s not really the primary focus for you to work on.
Based from my observation in the last couple of months, I find that all I need is 1 really good monitor, then everything else are extras.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lockdown Fatigue</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-27-lockdown-fatigue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-27-lockdown-fatigue/</guid>
      <description>Lockdown fatigue is real. At first, I thought that this is something that is just playing on my head that I can eventually overcome. It&amp;rsquo;s actually way tougher because you&amp;rsquo;re feeling a bit stuck in where you are. Physically, you can&amp;rsquo;t go anywhere else and movement makes you feel progress and general freedom.
The problem is that, there is no guarantee on when this will be over, or when things are going to ease up a little.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Minutes</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-26-five-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-26-five-minutes/</guid>
      <description>Five minutes seem to a be a lot of time but also too little in the grander scheme of things. You can a bug in a line of code, in few minutes, but it might take you days to solve the real issues around it. All you need is to make sure you try to achieve a very small task in least amount of time possible.
When writing these short snips of &amp;ldquo;freewriting&amp;rdquo;, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend more than 5 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wrong Side of the Bed</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-25-wrong-side-bed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-25-wrong-side-bed/</guid>
      <description>Waking up at the wrong side of the bed. That is a classic saying when it&amp;rsquo;s early in the morning and people around you notices that you&amp;rsquo;re not in the best mood as they observe your face. There are days when you wake up feeling sour and unproductive. You don&amp;rsquo;t feel like doing something productive like working on your goals, writing &amp;amp; journaling, or anything that requires a certain amount of effort to move.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Zones</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-24-time-zones/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-24-time-zones/</guid>
      <description>The concept of time zones are amazing and funny at the same time. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to know that the other side of the world would be sleeping while you&amp;rsquo;re awake. The weather differences are also interesting concepts. In this world where you can never have enough hours in a day, where you spend those times are increasingly becoming challenging.
In this &amp;ldquo;very connected&amp;rdquo; world, it&amp;rsquo;s now hard to find the optimal time to work with peers all over the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Server and Networking</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-23-server-networking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-23-server-networking/</guid>
      <description>Server networking and maintenance are the things I didn&amp;rsquo;t particularly like when I was younger. I really did like programming, coding, and general solutions architecture but I never really liked getting my hands dirty with server operations. Inevitably, it&amp;rsquo;s one of those things in life that you must have no matter what when working on a solution.
I actually ended up being good at it. I&amp;rsquo;m now maintaining couple of dozen of servers, infrastructure pipeline, containers &amp;amp; kubernetes, and different network security groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep Going</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-22-keep-going/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-22-keep-going/</guid>
      <description>A productive and &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; day can be ruined almost instantly before the day ends. It&amp;rsquo;s very important to set the night right in order for the next day to be meaningful and well energised. I find it troublesome to deal with if I have issues from the night before such as family and work problems. It bothers me a lot, even on the next day. This feeling is just soul crashing as if you&amp;rsquo;re not really in control of your own emotions and body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retirement</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-21-retirement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-21-retirement/</guid>
      <description>Retirement is a topic that I haven&amp;rsquo;t really figured out that much yet. I just know two fundamental things that would apply to me:
I need to set up a goal in terms of age or years where I should be &amp;ldquo;financially&amp;rdquo; independent. I need to find other things to do that are meaningful come that time. On the first topic of financial independence. What that means is that I don&amp;rsquo;t have to &amp;ldquo;work&amp;rdquo; in order to live like getting food or shelter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plants</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-20-plants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-20-plants/</guid>
      <description>Plants, plants, plants - and more plants. My wife is really into plants and I support her on to that one. We probably have a hundred plants right now at home, and that&amp;rsquo;s alright. I let her have that hobby and ownership of these cute little (and not so little) objects in our house. There will never be enough plants in our lives. They actually give good aesthetics to our place and makes it more breathable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning the week</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-19-planning-the-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-19-planning-the-week/</guid>
      <description>I like planning for the week ahead. It&amp;rsquo;s something I realised that is so effective in my line of work. If I don&amp;rsquo;t plan my schedule well, I will just be reactive of things and won&amp;rsquo;t have any focus. This usually leads to not being productive and a lot of demotivation. Although in the ideal world, things won&amp;rsquo;t go wrong and your schedule will just work - obviously that&amp;rsquo;s not the reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-18-breakfast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-18-breakfast/</guid>
      <description>Breakfast as they say is the most important meal of the day. I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure if that applies to me. I tend not to eat on breakfasts or just eat something small portioned instead. I tend to be more productive if I don&amp;rsquo;t feel bloated or dizzy after a very heavy meal. The problem that I have is that I have the impulse to overeat or stress eat, which is something I have to work on separately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunrise</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-17-sunrise/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-17-sunrise/</guid>
      <description>I like waking up early in the morning when everything is still quiet and calm. The sunrise gives me a feeling of warmth that radiates energy for the day ahead. This is a ceremony that it&amp;rsquo;s really a new day ahead.
I&amp;rsquo;m now re-developing a habit of waking up early again (sometime between 5:00 to 7:00 AM). Whenever I set myself for a successful morning, I know that I&amp;rsquo;ll stick to the routine all throughout the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Do</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-16-todo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-16-todo/</guid>
      <description>You don’t wake up thinking “What should I do today?” For sure, you know what you want to do, you know what you “need” to do. You know what will give you that 1% progress in your career goals, habits, and spiritual wellbeing.
You should instead wake up saying “I will do this.” I want to do this “because.” When you convince yourself that you will commit to the action, it propels to getting things done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-15-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-15-reading/</guid>
      <description>Reading is the most immersive and informative way of understanding a topic or subject. Although this takes a lot of time and effort, especially when you’re just beginning with your journey as a reader, it will be a fun and fulfilling activity to take daily. There is so much you can learn everyday just by reading. It will help you a lot in your career if you learn “how to learn”; and reading effectively is one principle that you have to understand and practice too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 hours of sleep</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-14-twelve-hour-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-14-twelve-hour-sleep/</guid>
      <description>12 hours of sleep. Wow, it’s been a while since I had that. I can’t really remember when was the last time that happened. It felt so good to be that energized and ready to become productive after a long, painful night of flu. I was alone in a comfortable bed mattress, it’s so quiet, and the weather &amp;amp; temperature was just right. It’s seldom that this happens. No phone calls, no disturbances, no notifications, no nothing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vaccines</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-13-vaccines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-13-vaccines/</guid>
      <description>I believe vaccines will save many people. I believe in the science behind it. Back in high school, it fascinated me about how vaccines are actually formed. It gave me some conviction that science is absolute and hard solid facts - not an opinion on your head. It is defined by certain rules, theories, and peer-reviewed by multiple smart people.
However, I don’t think it’s necessary for it to be a state or country mandate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asynchronous Work</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-12-asynchronous-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-12-asynchronous-work/</guid>
      <description>The workplace has transformed in the last 2 years because of the pandemic. There is now an emergence of concept around the type of work you do as a knowledge worker. There is synchronous and asynchronous work.
Synchronous work are the things when you have to be together and be in sync to do things together. These are usually held for workshops and meetings that there’s a clear contribution from everyone and a defined deadline to hit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chasing Success</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-11-chasing-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-11-chasing-success/</guid>
      <description>Don’t chase success, aim progress. It took me a while to get it, but that’s the reason I don’t feel excited or joyous anymore after achieving or hitting a milestone. The actual gold is the process and the experience that you get as part of achieving micro-goals. As we keep on saying, it’s about the journey and not the destination.
The problem I faced back in the day is that I thought I will just randomly feel the “motivation” hit or light bulb moment to be inspired to do something really special.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunsets</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-10-sunsets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-10-sunsets/</guid>
      <description>I like sunsets. It means a lot to me metaphorically. Romantically, I enjoyed seeing sunsets with my wife. There was this one time at a beach in the Philippines when we were riding a boat and we just looked at how beautiful the sunset was. That day is something I won’t ever forget.
The transition of day and night is fascinating because it gives you a clear boundary that you need to “change a state” from one to another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teminals</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-09-terminals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-09-terminals/</guid>
      <description>Terminals, shells, and CLIs are some of the recent things that I keep tinkering about. I like to make them colourful, using a lot of plugins to automate my typings, and all the goodness of just executing commands.
Back then, I was a GUI (Graphical User Interface) person, but I just found that for some advanced scenarios; I have to really use the command line to execute advanced commands or scripts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft Journey so Far</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-08-microsoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-08-microsoft/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft has been a big part of my career even until today. I don’t even know where to start my Microsoft journey. Maybe when I was a kid using a Windows PC Pentium 1? It was really when until I was around 17 when I got hooked because of being part of the [[Microsoft Student Partners]] program and got exposed to many people that I really liked. Obviously, there were also some inspirations with Bill Gates and Satya Nadella at my end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>That one thing</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-07-that-one-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-07-that-one-thing/</guid>
      <description>The first thing that I do when I wake up is to think of “that one thing” for the day. This ceremony has been embodied for me since I was young. I actually can’t remember who thought me about it, or if I got it from someone. It’s probably a product of laziness and procrastination, that I’ll just sleep on things and whatever I think about tomorrow will be the one I’ll be doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anger Management</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-06-anger-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-06-anger-management/</guid>
      <description>I would say that one of the best things that change in my character is how I can remain calm despite of stress and general disappointments in life. I realized it is so tiring to be angry with something if you know that it’s not really a battle worth fighting. I realized that you only have limited time in this world, and I don’t want to be live and be remembered as someone who is angry all the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self Manage</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-05-self-manage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-05-self-manage/</guid>
      <description>I consider myself as a self-managed individual in terms of career and lifestyle. It occurred to me I don’t want anyone to manage “me” personally in order to perform tasks and deliver results. This is not to be confused about having a project manager or coordinators I work with - most of them are outstanding. What I’m talking about are those who want to tell me how I should work or what I need to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early Bird</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-04-early-bird/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-04-early-bird/</guid>
      <description>I don’t really struggle to wake up early. Today I woke up at around 04:00 AM and it wasn’t a challenge at all. I am doing it because I find my writing and creative thinking to be early in the morning.
I am a mix of morning person and a night owl. I could spend the entire night being in the zone programming and solving problems, but I can also wake up early to begin my writing flow or do some “deep work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Media</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-03-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-03-social-media/</guid>
      <description>I’ve had a love and hate relationship with social media platforms in the past decade. Even until today, I haven’t really had a solid stance about these. I am aware of the dangers of these platforms when used excessively and inappropriately. I’ve tried shutting down my social media accounts from time to time. I keep creating new ones too. Right now, my Instagram is deactivated. I probably spend around 4 to 5 hours a week on these platforms (better that before).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Youtube</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-02-youtube/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-02-youtube/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been contemplating for a while now if I want to pursue creating videos for [[YouTube]] and [[Facebook]]. I have a lot of ideas on various topics, such as from creating video tutorials, to talk about life and my family. One thing that I want to cover in my personal career is the things that I’m working on in the AI, IoT and Edge space. I am thinking of doing some live streaming of learning from [[Microsoft Learn]] as well as from other source material such as [[Ethereum]].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Everyday</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-01-writing-everyday/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-09-01-writing-everyday/</guid>
      <description>Writing every day is one of my goals for this year. I think I’m doing really well on that front. Obviously there are days I wasn’t able to write about because of various reasons such as being on a holiday or focusing on other activities, but the habit is there and well developed already. I keep a journal of what’s on my head and what I’m feeling, as this is the only way to make myself sane at this pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Messaging</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-30-messaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-30-messaging/</guid>
      <description>Messaging is probably one of the most interesting topic in software for me. This is a state when a “message” is being sent from an origin to a destination. Traditionally, a user interface can directly call a backend service, and then that backend service goes straight in to inserting a record to a database. But that was like decades ago. Since then, a lot of improvements already happened. Messaging came to the rescue in order to handle millions and billions of concurrent transactions happening around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cleaning</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-29-cleaning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-29-cleaning/</guid>
      <description>Cleaning as a concept is very foreign to me until I became fully independent in life. I didn’t really understand back then the reason I should clean anything. The problem was, someone else has always been doing it for me. I don’t see the value of doing it, or I have some pride about someone else should do it. A chore is something that is coined as “free work” hence, I don’t get incentivised in doing it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaming</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-28-gaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-28-gaming/</guid>
      <description>I don’t really consider myself as a hardcore gamer. At least right now. I’ve always been a casual gamer, where I enjoyed it the most when I’m playing with friends or trying to immerse with the story. Gone are the days where I have spent countless hours of my life just trying to “level-up” on a game and increase a virtual attribute of my character. There’s just so much else to work on instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to Normal</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-27-back-to-normal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-27-back-to-normal/</guid>
      <description>There is no going back to normal. It took me a while to get it, but that is the sad and harsh truth. Our lives have changed in the past two years, that I can’t actually imagine how “normal” will actually look like. I know it’s depressing. Even for a very optimistic like me, I am still getting the toll of the lockdowns, the COVID-19 news. It’s a lot of emotions to take in once you get succumb to social media and the news, it’s like the world is just ending.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pair Programming</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-26-pair-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-26-pair-programming/</guid>
      <description>Collaborating using share screen is fun. I think this is the modern way of doing pair-programming. This is a very efficient method for both people to learn, share ideas, and collaborate. I recently have done it, and I would guarantee that we’ve done more work together than doing things separately. It’s very important, especially if you’re at the early phase of the project, to foster collaboration. The underlying foundations of the work that you’re doing are very critical in the beginning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Mind</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-25-human-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-25-human-mind/</guid>
      <description>The human mind and body are funny and amazing at the same time. We do a lot of things that make little sense on a high level or just by looking at it literally. One example I keep thinking about is the concept of “resting” such as taking sleeps, naps, or doing recreational activities. We’re unique as species because we have our own concept of “motivation” and rationale to answer “why you want to do it”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Cloud</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-24-hybrid-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-24-hybrid-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Hybrid cloud is the trend right now I see in a lot of companies and enterprises. The term hybrid has grown too in the last couple of years. It just showed connectivity between an on-premises data center to public clouds like AWS and Azure. This time, hybrid now also means multi-cloud strategy and edge computing. It’s about borderless connectivity across different topologies or deployment models happening around.
Edge computing is an interest to me, because there are a lot of operations that would make sense in an isolated environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master Plan</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-23-master-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-23-master-plan/</guid>
      <description>All things that need to be built have some sort of “master plan.” When you’re building a house or a building, you have a reference point of what it would look like in a design document. It’s good to have this, because the effort and cost of constructing projects would be costly. It’s good to have a plan early on.
Now that I’m reflecting about it in the Software and IT industry, we don’t use that much “Master Document” anymore, since projects and products constantly develop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grief</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-22-grief/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-22-grief/</guid>
      <description>Grief is one of the most difficult feeling in this world. This is probably the most painful emotional response to what&amp;rsquo;s happening in your world. In my opinion, when this happens to you, it challenges all of your pre-conceived knowledge and beliefs in life. You question about everything: from science, philosophy, behaviour, religion, and so on. You get in to a dark place in a rabbit hole of questions. You contemplate about the meaning of life, and what is your purpose in this world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking in Pictures</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-21-thinking-in-pictures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-21-thinking-in-pictures/</guid>
      <description>My brain works better when I think in pictures. This is probably why I thrive as a software engineer and architect. I can easily visualize data flows and business requirements; then translate them into something technical that we can implement. I have not really undergone any serious tests or evaluation, but I’m really at my best when I can visualize things.
That’s probably why I enjoy seeing architecture diagrams and love doing them too!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-20-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-20-security/</guid>
      <description>Security is such a broad topic but is simple in principle. It’s about protecting something, either that is you, your family, or properties against unwanted scenarios. This applies to a lot of different domains such as in physical properties like your home and workplace, and as well as in your digital life, such as computers, software, banking systems, and so on.
Depending on which domain, there are also different levels and approaches to security.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-19-energy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-19-energy/</guid>
      <description>When I was younger, I thought that you have an unlimited number of energy in a day. You can do school, play games, interact with friends &amp;amp; family, do homework, and even dream about what’s going to happen tomorrow. I can still remember my young self, who has the bravado and burning passion that I can always do the extra mile.
Now that I’m an adult, I’ve come to a realisation that your energy in a day is actually very limited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anime</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-18-anime/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-18-anime/</guid>
      <description>Anime has been a big part of my childhood. The young me have watched, read, and played various anime media content. I was so hooked on it back in the days. I’m always up to date with manga content of One Piece, Naruto, Bleach, and all the similar genres. It even helped me cope up with some “teens” problem or, as you know it, the “finding your inner self” kind of thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coffee</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-17-coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-17-coffee/</guid>
      <description>Coffee has been a big part of my life for the past decade. For obvious reasons like keeping me wake up at night doing some work, to making sure I’m well energized in the morning. There was a period in my life that I was probably close to drinking 6 shots a day, but I already gave up that lifestyle.
I have learned to tone down with it, because I already realized my limit on energy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organising calendars</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-16-calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-16-calendar/</guid>
      <description>Organising my calendar has been my system since I was in college. It means a lot to me when I know that it’s in my outlook calendar. It’s like saying you’re going to credit a portion of your life to do something at that specific point in time. This allows me to plan and prioritise ahead on what’s really important.
Right now, I have around 5 calendars: 1 for Personal &amp;amp; Family event, 1 for health like running schedules and meal plans, 1 for my consulting business, 1 for my startup venture, and the other 1 for my long-term contract client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean Desk</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-15-clean-desk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-15-clean-desk/</guid>
      <description>Having a clean desk is something I aspire to every now and then. I’ve been trying to find different ways to have an optimise working environment for my creative and logical output (programming and presenting). When my desk is clean and in order, that’s when I get to have a lot of things done. The less I see, the more output I provide.
That’s why these days, when I don’t need something, I put it in my bad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watching Movies</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-14-watching-movies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-14-watching-movies/</guid>
      <description>Watching movies is my hobby. It’s been like that since I was young. I think it all began when I was so fascinated with advanced graphic designs of things. The likes of Star Wars and Lord of the Rings are just so immersive during those times that I really felt the action and depth of the stories. I’ve probably watched like a lot of movies. Back when cinemas were still a thing, I would always like to watch expected movies on its first week of release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Losing Weight</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-13-losing-weight/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-13-losing-weight/</guid>
      <description>Losing weight is actually very simple. You’ll literally just have to eat less. It’s that simple. Then, of course, losing weight does not really equate to being healthy. You can lose weight by cutting a lot of sugar and carbs in few weeks or months, then eventually succumb back to old habits. Well, you’ve achieved your goal of “losing weight”, but you see&amp;hellip; you didn’t develop a lifestyle of being healthy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event Planning</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-12-event-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-12-event-planning/</guid>
      <description>Planning an event is both fun and frustrating at the same time. It&amp;rsquo;s fun because you get to do something that is servicing for others (such as a community or group of people). There are so many thing that you can learn in the process from understanding different people&amp;rsquo;s perspectives and likeness, to the variety of topics, to understanding the current industry trends, and the list goes on. It is sometimes frustrating because there are just too many unknowns before, during, and after the events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friendship</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-11-friendship/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-11-friendship/</guid>
      <description>There are so many things you can talk about, friendship. I would like to focus on the benefits and the positive side of it, rather than the downside. There are reasons you would want to have friends or be friend with someone. Well, for one, we survived as species by having a collection of like-minded people - aka tribes. Although not all the members of the tribe can be your friend, you accept someone else to be part of your life - and vice versa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NFTs</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-10-nfts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-10-nfts/</guid>
      <description>Non-Fungible Tokens or also known as NFTs are a big hype right now. It’s been around for quite some time now, but we’re just seeing more use cases and platforms emerging as part of this trend. We are now seeing more and more projects trying to “tokenise” a physical or digital asset.
I believe in this use case of [[Blockchain]], and I can argue that it’s probably one of the very few proper use cases of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sydney</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-09-sydney/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-09-sydney/</guid>
      <description>Sydney is home for me. When I first came here on 2011, I already knew that this place is home and this is where I want to grow a family. There are so many things I like about Sydney: having both my sisters here and extended family, from food and people diversity, a lot of friends I met along the way. It brought me a lot of opportunity, from being a coder, consultant, and entrepreneur; I thrived in this place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mental Block</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-08-mental-block/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-08-mental-block/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes we experience a state of &amp;ldquo;mental block&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s when we can&amp;rsquo;t think creatively or logically to solve a specific problem. This happens for a lot of reasons such as lack of energy, hunger, distraction, and lack of comprehension to the subject matter.
Whenever I get stuck with a problem, I leave it on a state when I can resume it later on. That means I have to make sure I capture all the important notes about it before I leave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trust</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-07-trust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-07-trust/</guid>
      <description>Trust is a currency that is both common and unique to humanity. Before currencies came to life, we use trust as the means of transaction. Even until now, with all the cryptocurrencies and related technologies, it&amp;rsquo;s still Trust that we are trying to bridge the gap. These technologies just advance the automation and the &amp;ldquo;skunk work&amp;rdquo; from an operations stand point, but the actual entity who represents it cannot be replaced with an AI (or at least far from it right now).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Midnight Oil</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-06-midnight-oil/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-06-midnight-oil/</guid>
      <description>There are some legitimate excuse in my opinion to burn the midnight oil - aka work late at night. I do this so that I don&amp;rsquo;t have to work over the weekends, and I can spend a lot of quality time with my family. This also allows me to work on a task that I know I can finish, or at least hit a milestone of, instead of procrastinating it for the next day or week (something I&amp;rsquo;ve done a lot in the past).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Season</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-05-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-05-season/</guid>
      <description>Winter, spring, summer, or fall - I love bits and pieces of them. I love that on winter I can have a cool environment to sleep on. I hate winter, because it gets dark too early! I love spring because of the beautiful plants and flowers around, but I also hate it because of hay fever. I love summer because it&amp;rsquo;s the best time to go to the beach and you have a lot of day time to spend outside business hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-04-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-04-community/</guid>
      <description>Community is a place where you find people with similar interests or profession. I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved with the tech community for a decade now, and I still love meeting new people and talk about ideas, problems, and solutions about tech! I present to these community groups from time to time, and would continue doing it for the years to come. It&amp;rsquo;s because of the community, that I get to progress in my career.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-03-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-03-practice/</guid>
      <description>Practice makes perfect. Maybe not &amp;ldquo;perfect&amp;rdquo; for everyone, but close to the objective or your goal. It takes a lot of repetition to truly master a craft or a profession, you need to spend a lot of those hours in order to learn what works and what doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. For most of the time, practicing is a mental game of repetition in order to really &amp;ldquo;nail it.&amp;rdquo; You can&amp;rsquo;t just be an expert to a specific topic overnight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a House</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-02-building-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-02-building-house/</guid>
      <description>Building a house is not easy. There are so many things involved and it can get complicated and complex really quick. There are just so many things to consider such as the price, design, and a lot of other things. It&amp;rsquo;s a process that you have to undergo if you want to really become invested emotionally to the property that you&amp;rsquo;re building. It takes a lot of sleepless nights and divided attention, not to mention the anxiety that this brings on your head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekends</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-01-weekends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-08-01-weekends/</guid>
      <description>Weekends are very important to me now. Back then, I treat it as a way to do more work while others are busy with their personal lives. That was so wrong in so many levels. For one, you need the actual rest so that you&amp;rsquo;ll have the energy and motivation for the week ahead. Another thing is that, it&amp;rsquo;s also the time to do things that you don&amp;rsquo;t normally do during work time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Startup</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-31-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-31-startup/</guid>
      <description>Joining or starting a start-up is not as simple as it could be. There are a lot of complexity involved. From finding and partnering with the right set of people, to creating and building the actual product. This is a very competitive space and would require a lot of energy, passion, and attention. Unlike a side-project that you can just run, a startup requires focus and product market fit. If you have the time, energy, and resources I would advise for you t o give it a try.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-30-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-30-markdown/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m particularly liking the Markdown format in creating notes. Thanks to [[RoamResearch]] and [[Hugo]] (with the whole JAMstack craze), I am being sucked in this cult. I am actually realizing the benefits as I have more structure on my thoughts and flow of information. I follow a format that would work to most systems these days, and it&amp;rsquo;s easy to convert and transpose anywhere.
I am still learning some of the advanced capabilities of Markdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcasts</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-29-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-29-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s fun recording podcasts episode as this is a way for me to learn (or refresh) on topics with a different perspective. It is also an interactive way for me to meet and know more about the person. These days, [[Bryan Anthony Garcia]] and I are doing [[The Battle of Clouds]] and it&amp;rsquo;s a good way to immortalize topics. We give it a twist in a way that it&amp;rsquo;s catered to young Filipino audience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overwhelmed</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-28-overwhelmed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-28-overwhelmed/</guid>
      <description>Overwhelmed. I think that&amp;rsquo;s a state when you have a lot of things in your mind and you&amp;rsquo;re fighting an internal battle on how to deal with your problems. Sometimes the answers are not very clear and you don&amp;rsquo;t have the answers right away. To overcome this state, you have to stop what you&amp;rsquo;re doing and try to look from a far. You have to re-organize your thoughts on what&amp;rsquo;s really important and what&amp;rsquo;s urgent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivation</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-26-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-26-motivation/</guid>
      <description>Motivation is something that everyone needs in order to thrive in their day. Having motivation is like taking a bath: not because you had it yesterday, you&amp;rsquo;ll be okay for today and tomorrow. It&amp;rsquo;s a constant energy that fuels us to drive the pathway of chaos. We can get motivation from finishing goals, acquiring things, or when we feel valued. There are many ways to attain it, even simple meditation or exercise can do the trick sometimes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-27-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-27-running/</guid>
      <description>Running is an activity that I particularly like. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of rules, and it&amp;rsquo;s a sport or game that is natural to all of us humans. It&amp;rsquo;s something you can do as a group or alone, again not much rules. I find running &amp;ldquo;meditative&amp;rdquo; as this allows me to wrap around my head in terms of flow of thoughts and how to solve or approach a specific problem at hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Productive Day</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-26-productive-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-26-productive-day/</guid>
      <description>A productive day at work means I get to finish tasks that I committed on time. This rarely happens because either the estimates are wrong, or there are just so many things that happens unexpectedly. I like having these days when I get to move on to the task at hand without allotting them some mental space on my head while I an with my family or during extra curricular activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listen</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-25-listen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-25-listen/</guid>
      <description>Learn to shut up. It&amp;rsquo;s easier said than done. Especially if you grew up to speak what&amp;rsquo;s on your mind. However, we weren&amp;rsquo;t taught how to listen - like properly listen to a person, surrounding, a video, and even thoughts. There are so many things in this life that you can learn if you just sit, focus, and listen carefully. Listen. You can talk when it&amp;rsquo;s the right time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfect</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-24-perfect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-24-perfect/</guid>
      <description>There is no such thing as perfect. You&amp;rsquo;ll just have to chase what&amp;rsquo;s going to be perfect for you. You will feel constant disappointment time and time again. Once you&amp;rsquo;re in that treadmill of chasing perfection, you just keep getting hungry the further you go. Perfection is an enemy that most of us face when we&amp;rsquo;re trying to do creative work like writing, coding, speaking, and art work. However, don&amp;rsquo;t settle to mediocre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleep</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-23-focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-23-focus/</guid>
      <description>Focus is very important. This is what sets a task to be done in months or days into hours and minutes. Having focus means having the dexterity to know where to shoot your arrow. For me to be in focus, I need to be in flow. I was a victim of being a &amp;ldquo;hardworker&amp;rdquo; in the past, where I burn the midnight oil to non-valuable things.
I need to make sure I setup my mindset and environment to respect my thought processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleep</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-22-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-22-sleep/</guid>
      <description>Sleep is very important for the obvious health reasons. What I also found out is that having a good sleep allows me to be a creative thinker when I have to think of new ideas. I do have a habit of staying up late if I need or want to finish something. If the means to do it is already defined, such as programming a module with clear business requirements - all I need is the time, focus, and resources to do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deadlines</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-21-deadlines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-21-deadlines/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes I don&amp;rsquo;t believe that there is such thing as a &amp;ldquo;deadline&amp;rdquo; or end of life for a project. You just define what you want to build given the time, resources, and talent that is available for you. A deadline could probably be re-word as a milestone or a target, in which there is a certain state that you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a product to be developed. Deadlines are stressful, I want to avoid that word.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binaural Beats</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-20-binaural-beats/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-20-binaural-beats/</guid>
      <description>[[Binaural Beats]] is a type of music that really works for me. It helps me stay relaxed, calm, and focused. This is my go to playlist when I need to work at night. This is particularly useful if I already know what I need to do, and I just need the right set of mindset to execute them. I would recommend it to anyone who is looking for a go to music while doing creative or logical work such as programming or writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieving Success</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-19-achieving-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-19-achieving-success/</guid>
      <description>Achieving &amp;ldquo;success&amp;rdquo; is actually very simple, but the process is often hard. For example, you want to be an author, all you have to do is to keep on writing - over and over, day in and out. You won&amp;rsquo;t be an author &amp;ldquo;overnight&amp;rdquo; per-se, it&amp;rsquo;s those thousands and millions of words that come out of your mind and the hundreds of revisions that will make you an author.
The same applies to being an entrepreneur, all you have to do is to keep on exploring business opportunities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is success?</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-18-what-is-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-18-what-is-success/</guid>
      <description>What is success? Spoiler alert: It&amp;rsquo;s relative. What it means is that success would mean differently to each and every individual. Other would consider having a lot of money as successful. For some, it&amp;rsquo;s about having influence and fanbase. Others is about being a CEO or Director of a company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Influencers</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-17-online-influencers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-17-online-influencers/</guid>
      <description>Be careful with influencers. Most of the time, they are after their own agenda. You&amp;rsquo;re just a number in their likes, views, and subscribers.
There are dangers of being a consumer of a product - excessively. Participate when you can. Add a comment, share your insights, write about what you think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep on Writing</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-16-keep-on-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-16-keep-on-writing/</guid>
      <description>I have to keep on writing. Write what I feel. Write what I know. Start it, even if it’s just a draft. I have to keep on writing because eventually I will forget what’s on my head right now, I will forget what I’m feeling, I will forget the person living inside my body today. Write so that I can re-live each and every moment of it.
I want to write all sorts of topic, from [DeFi] and [Blockchain], to [Microsoft Azure] and [DotNet5].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feeling Nervous</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-15-feeling-nervous/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-15-feeling-nervous/</guid>
      <description>It’s few minutes before my talk, and I still feel a little bit nervous about it. I’ve been speaking to conferences for almost a decade now and I had all sorts of experiences with it already.
I’t okay to feel nervous, it means that you care about the event that is about to happen. It means that something alongside you values that aspect of life. Speaking is one of those things that I still get nervous time and time again, because I still care about it, I still want to improve about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being Busy</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-14-being-busy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 03:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-14-being-busy/</guid>
      <description>Being busy does not always equate to being productive. You can just be in a state of busy because you think you&amp;rsquo;re doing something important. Sometimes, what you need is not &amp;ldquo;to be busy&amp;rdquo;, but &amp;ldquo;to be focused&amp;rdquo; on a task at hand. Time management is always the key to ensure that you get the right things done in your glorified to do list. Next time, instead of saying &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m busy&amp;rdquo;, say something like &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll be working on&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;I have an urgent thing to finish, I&amp;rsquo;ll be right back to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boredom</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-13-boredom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 02:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>michael@datachain.consulting (Michael John Peña)</author>
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/status/2021-07-13-boredom/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s okay to be bored from time to time. It means that you don&amp;rsquo;t have something that is urgent and important. It&amp;rsquo;s bad to be bored if it&amp;rsquo;s a coping mechanism to avoid stress. A right amount of stress is good for you, to keep you challenged and energised - also in a way have purpose in life. Aim to have boring days, so that out of the stressful day, you have some time to recharge and contemplate on what&amp;rsquo;s really important for you.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
