<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mlogs on ⚡️ Michael John Peña</title>
    <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mlogs on ⚡️ Michael John Peña</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>- Michael John Peña</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Community</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-08-04-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-08-04-community/</guid>
      <description>Community is a place where you find people with similar interests or profession. I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved with the tech community for a decade now, and I still love meeting new people and talk about ideas, problems, and solutions about tech! I present to these community groups from time to time, and would continue doing it for the years to come. It&amp;rsquo;s because of the community, that I get to progress in my career.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-08-03-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-08-03-practice/</guid>
      <description>Practice makes perfect. Maybe not &amp;ldquo;perfect&amp;rdquo; for everyone, but close to the objective or your goal. It takes a lot of repetition to truly master a craft or a profession, you need to spend a lot of those hours in order to learn what works and what doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. For most of the time, practicing is a mental game of repetition in order to really &amp;ldquo;nail it.&amp;rdquo; You can&amp;rsquo;t just be an expert to a specific topic overnight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a House</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-08-02-building-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-08-02-building-house/</guid>
      <description>Building a house is not easy. There are so many things involved and it can get complicated and complex really quick. There are just so many things to consider such as the price, design, and a lot of other things. It&amp;rsquo;s a process that you have to undergo if you want to really become invested emotionally to the property that you&amp;rsquo;re building. It takes a lot of sleepless nights and divided attention, not to mention the anxiety that this brings on your head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekends</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-08-01-weekends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-08-01-weekends/</guid>
      <description>Weekends are very important to me now. Back then, I treat it as a way to do more work while others are busy with their personal lives. That was so wrong in so many levels. For one, you need the actual rest so that you&amp;rsquo;ll have the energy and motivation for the week ahead. Another thing is that, it&amp;rsquo;s also the time to do things that you don&amp;rsquo;t normally do during work time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Startup</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-31-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-31-startup/</guid>
      <description>Joining or starting a start-up is not as simple as it could be. There are a lot of complexity involved. From finding and partnering with the right set of people, to creating and building the actual product. This is a very competitive space and would require a lot of energy, passion, and attention. Unlike a side-project that you can just run, a startup requires focus and product market fit. If you have the time, energy, and resources I would advise for you t o give it a try.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-30-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-30-markdown/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m particularly liking the Markdown format in creating notes. Thanks to [[RoamResearch]] and [[Hugo]] (with the whole JAMstack craze), I am being sucked in this cult. I am actually realizing the benefits as I have more structure on my thoughts and flow of information. I follow a format that would work to most systems these days, and it&amp;rsquo;s easy to convert and transpose anywhere.
I am still learning some of the advanced capabilities of Markdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcasts</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-29-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-29-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s fun recording podcasts episode as this is a way for me to learn (or refresh) on topics with a different perspective. It is also an interactive way for me to meet and know more about the person. These days, [[Bryan Anthony Garcia]] and I are doing [[The Battle of Clouds]] and it&amp;rsquo;s a good way to immortalize topics. We give it a twist in a way that it&amp;rsquo;s catered to young Filipino audience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overwhelmed</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-28-overwhelmed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-28-overwhelmed/</guid>
      <description>Overwhelmed. I think that&amp;rsquo;s a state when you have a lot of things in your mind and you&amp;rsquo;re fighting an internal battle on how to deal with your problems. Sometimes the answers are not very clear and you don&amp;rsquo;t have the answers right away. To overcome this state, you have to stop what you&amp;rsquo;re doing and try to look from a far. You have to re-organize your thoughts on what&amp;rsquo;s really important and what&amp;rsquo;s urgent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivation</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-26-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-26-motivation/</guid>
      <description>Motivation is something that everyone needs in order to thrive in their day. Having motivation is like taking a bath: not because you had it yesterday, you&amp;rsquo;ll be okay for today and tomorrow. It&amp;rsquo;s a constant energy that fuels us to drive the pathway of chaos. We can get motivation from finishing goals, acquiring things, or when we feel valued. There are many ways to attain it, even simple meditation or exercise can do the trick sometimes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-27-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-27-running/</guid>
      <description>Running is an activity that I particularly like. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of rules, and it&amp;rsquo;s a sport or game that is natural to all of us humans. It&amp;rsquo;s something you can do as a group or alone, again not much rules. I find running &amp;ldquo;meditative&amp;rdquo; as this allows me to wrap around my head in terms of flow of thoughts and how to solve or approach a specific problem at hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Productive Day</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-26-productive-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-26-productive-day/</guid>
      <description>A productive day at work means I get to finish tasks that I committed on time. This rarely happens because either the estimates are wrong, or there are just so many things that happens unexpectedly. I like having these days when I get to move on to the task at hand without allotting them some mental space on my head while I an with my family or during extra curricular activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listen</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-25-listen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-25-listen/</guid>
      <description>Learn to shut up. It&amp;rsquo;s easier said than done. Especially if you grew up to speak what&amp;rsquo;s on your mind. However, we weren&amp;rsquo;t taught how to listen - like properly listen to a person, surrounding, a video, and even thoughts. There are so many things in this life that you can learn if you just sit, focus, and listen carefully. Listen. You can talk when it&amp;rsquo;s the right time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfect</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-24-perfect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-24-perfect/</guid>
      <description>There is no such thing as perfect. You&amp;rsquo;ll just have to chase what&amp;rsquo;s going to be perfect for you. You will feel constant disappointment time and time again. Once you&amp;rsquo;re in that treadmill of chasing perfection, you just keep getting hungry the further you go. Perfection is an enemy that most of us face when we&amp;rsquo;re trying to do creative work like writing, coding, speaking, and art work. However, don&amp;rsquo;t settle to mediocre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleep</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-23-focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-23-focus/</guid>
      <description>Focus is very important. This is what sets a task to be done in months or days into hours and minutes. Having focus means having the dexterity to know where to shoot your arrow. For me to be in focus, I need to be in flow. I was a victim of being a &amp;ldquo;hardworker&amp;rdquo; in the past, where I burn the midnight oil to non-valuable things.
I need to make sure I setup my mindset and environment to respect my thought processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleep</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-22-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-22-sleep/</guid>
      <description>Sleep is very important for the obvious health reasons. What I also found out is that having a good sleep allows me to be a creative thinker when I have to think of new ideas. I do have a habit of staying up late if I need or want to finish something. If the means to do it is already defined, such as programming a module with clear business requirements - all I need is the time, focus, and resources to do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deadlines</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-21-deadlines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-21-deadlines/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes I don&amp;rsquo;t believe that there is such thing as a &amp;ldquo;deadline&amp;rdquo; or end of life for a project. You just define what you want to build given the time, resources, and talent that is available for you. A deadline could probably be re-word as a milestone or a target, in which there is a certain state that you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a product to be developed. Deadlines are stressful, I want to avoid that word.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binaural Beats</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-20-binaural-beats/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-20-binaural-beats/</guid>
      <description>[[Binaural Beats]] is a type of music that really works for me. It helps me stay relaxed, calm, and focused. This is my go to playlist when I need to work at night. This is particularly useful if I already know what I need to do, and I just need the right set of mindset to execute them. I would recommend it to anyone who is looking for a go to music while doing creative or logical work such as programming or writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieving Success</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-19-achieving-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-19-achieving-success/</guid>
      <description>Achieving &amp;ldquo;success&amp;rdquo; is actually very simple, but the process is often hard. For example, you want to be an author, all you have to do is to keep on writing - over and over, day in and out. You won&amp;rsquo;t be an author &amp;ldquo;overnight&amp;rdquo; per-se, it&amp;rsquo;s those thousands and millions of words that come out of your mind and the hundreds of revisions that will make you an author.
The same applies to being an entrepreneur, all you have to do is to keep on exploring business opportunities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is success?</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-18-what-is-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-18-what-is-success/</guid>
      <description>What is success? Spoiler alert: It&amp;rsquo;s relative. What it means is that success would mean differently to each and every individual. Other would consider having a lot of money as successful. For some, it&amp;rsquo;s about having influence and fanbase. Others is about being a CEO or Director of a company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Influencers</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-17-online-influencers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-17-online-influencers/</guid>
      <description>Be careful with influencers. Most of the time, they are after their own agenda. You&amp;rsquo;re just a number in their likes, views, and subscribers.
There are dangers of being a consumer of a product - excessively. Participate when you can. Add a comment, share your insights, write about what you think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep on Writing</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-16-keep-on-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-16-keep-on-writing/</guid>
      <description>I have to keep on writing. Write what I feel. Write what I know. Start it, even if it’s just a draft. I have to keep on writing because eventually I will forget what’s on my head right now, I will forget what I’m feeling, I will forget the person living inside my body today. Write so that I can re-live each and every moment of it.
I want to write all sorts of topic, from [DeFi] and [Blockchain], to [Microsoft Azure] and [DotNet5].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feeling Nervous</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-15-feeling-nervous/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-15-feeling-nervous/</guid>
      <description>It’s few minutes before my talk, and I still feel a little bit nervous about it. I’ve been speaking to conferences for almost a decade now and I had all sorts of experiences with it already.
I’t okay to feel nervous, it means that you care about the event that is about to happen. It means that something alongside you values that aspect of life. Speaking is one of those things that I still get nervous time and time again, because I still care about it, I still want to improve about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being Busy</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-14-being-busy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 03:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-14-being-busy/</guid>
      <description>Being busy does not always equate to being productive. You can just be in a state of busy because you think you&amp;rsquo;re doing something important. Sometimes, what you need is not &amp;ldquo;to be busy&amp;rdquo;, but &amp;ldquo;to be focused&amp;rdquo; on a task at hand. Time management is always the key to ensure that you get the right things done in your glorified to do list. Next time, instead of saying &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m busy&amp;rdquo;, say something like &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll be working on&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;I have an urgent thing to finish, I&amp;rsquo;ll be right back to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boredom</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-13-boredom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 02:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-13-boredom/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s okay to be bored from time to time. It means that you don&amp;rsquo;t have something that is urgent and important. It&amp;rsquo;s bad to be bored if it&amp;rsquo;s a coping mechanism to avoid stress. A right amount of stress is good for you, to keep you challenged and energised - also in a way have purpose in life. Aim to have boring days, so that out of the stressful day, you have some time to recharge and contemplate on what&amp;rsquo;s really important for you.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
