<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>productivity on ⚡️ Michael John Peña</title>
    <link>https://mjtpena.github.io/public/tags/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in productivity on ⚡️ Michael John Peña</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Michael John Peña 2021</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:47:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mjtpena.github.io/public/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to beat procrastination</title>
      <link>https://mjtpena.github.io/public/blog/how-to-beat-procrastination/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjtpena.github.io/public/blog/how-to-beat-procrastination/</guid>
      <description>One of the colossal beasts that all knowledge workers fight time and time again is procrastination. This is when you know you should work, but you don&amp;rsquo;t have enough willpower to do it. You can&amp;rsquo;t code, you can&amp;rsquo;t do that design document, you can&amp;rsquo;t write that next blog post&amp;hellip; the list goes on. Here are 5 of my usual methods when I&amp;rsquo;m stuck in that limbo.
Avoid Distractions The first and obvious thing that you have to do is to avoid distraction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Intentionalization: Don’t click that next button</title>
      <link>https://mjtpena.github.io/public/blog/digital-intentionalization-dont-click-that-next-button/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 22:29:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjtpena.github.io/public/blog/digital-intentionalization-dont-click-that-next-button/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s very tempting to click on &amp;ldquo;that next button&amp;rdquo; wether that is from YouTube, Netflix, Facebook videos or any endless buffet of consumption. You start watching a video about a topic you&amp;rsquo;re really interested in to and end up watching something weird after 3 hours. As I do more research in my personal journey of Digital Intentionalization, this is probably one of the most obvious ones. We let the platform play the next content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My only goal for 2021: Digital Intentionality</title>
      <link>https://mjtpena.github.io/public/blog/my-only-goal-for-2021-digital-intentionality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 23:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mjtpena.github.io/public/blog/my-only-goal-for-2021-digital-intentionality/</guid>
      <description>During the holidays, I was contemplating on what skills should I invest time on for 2021. As someone who is working in the technology field, there are a lot of exciting things to double-down on: from Artificial Intelligence (AI), Internet of Things (IoT), Blockchain, and a plethora of technology trends. As I reflected on how my 2020 went in terms of career and lifestyle, I noticed that there is an area I really need to work on - my digital life.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
