<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>⚡️ Michael John Peña</title>
    <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ⚡️ Michael John Peña</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>- Michael John Peña</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building a House</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-08-02-building-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-08-02-building-house/</guid>
      <description>Building a house is not easy. There are so many things involved and it can get complicated and complex really quick. There are just so many things to consider such as the price, design, and a lot of other things. It&amp;rsquo;s a process that you have to undergo if you want to really become invested emotionally to the property that you&amp;rsquo;re building. It takes a lot of sleepless nights and divided attention, not to mention the anxiety that this brings on your head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekends</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-08-01-weekends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-08-01-weekends/</guid>
      <description>Weekends are very important to me now. Back then, I treat it as a way to do more work while others are busy with their personal lives. That was so wrong in so many levels. For one, you need the actual rest so that you&amp;rsquo;ll have the energy and motivation for the week ahead. Another thing is that, it&amp;rsquo;s also the time to do things that you don&amp;rsquo;t normally do during work time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Startup</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-31-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-31-startup/</guid>
      <description>Joining or starting a start-up is not as simple as it could be. There are a lot of complexity involved. From finding and partnering with the right set of people, to creating and building the actual product. This is a very competitive space and would require a lot of energy, passion, and attention. Unlike a side-project that you can just run, a startup requires focus and product market fit. If you have the time, energy, and resources I would advise for you t o give it a try.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-30-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-30-markdown/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m particularly liking the Markdown format in creating notes. Thanks to [[RoamResearch]] and [[Hugo]] (with the whole JAMstack craze), I am being sucked in this cult. I am actually realizing the benefits as I have more structure on my thoughts and flow of information. I follow a format that would work to most systems these days, and it&amp;rsquo;s easy to convert and transpose anywhere.
I am still learning some of the advanced capabilities of Markdown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcasts</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-29-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-29-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s fun recording podcasts episode as this is a way for me to learn (or refresh) on topics with a different perspective. It is also an interactive way for me to meet and know more about the person. These days, [[Bryan Anthony Garcia]] and I are doing [[The Battle of Clouds]] and it&amp;rsquo;s a good way to immortalize topics. We give it a twist in a way that it&amp;rsquo;s catered to young Filipino audience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overwhelmed</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-28-overwhelmed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-28-overwhelmed/</guid>
      <description>Overwhelmed. I think that&amp;rsquo;s a state when you have a lot of things in your mind and you&amp;rsquo;re fighting an internal battle on how to deal with your problems. Sometimes the answers are not very clear and you don&amp;rsquo;t have the answers right away. To overcome this state, you have to stop what you&amp;rsquo;re doing and try to look from a far. You have to re-organize your thoughts on what&amp;rsquo;s really important and what&amp;rsquo;s urgent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivation</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-26-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-26-motivation/</guid>
      <description>Motivation is something that everyone needs in order to thrive in their day. Having motivation is like taking a bath: not because you had it yesterday, you&amp;rsquo;ll be okay for today and tomorrow. It&amp;rsquo;s a constant energy that fuels us to drive the pathway of chaos. We can get motivation from finishing goals, acquiring things, or when we feel valued. There are many ways to attain it, even simple meditation or exercise can do the trick sometimes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-27-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-27-running/</guid>
      <description>Running is an activity that I particularly like. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of rules, and it&amp;rsquo;s a sport or game that is natural to all of us humans. It&amp;rsquo;s something you can do as a group or alone, again not much rules. I find running &amp;ldquo;meditative&amp;rdquo; as this allows me to wrap around my head in terms of flow of thoughts and how to solve or approach a specific problem at hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Productive Day</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-26-productive-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-26-productive-day/</guid>
      <description>A productive day at work means I get to finish tasks that I committed on time. This rarely happens because either the estimates are wrong, or there are just so many things that happens unexpectedly. I like having these days when I get to move on to the task at hand without allotting them some mental space on my head while I an with my family or during extra curricular activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Listen</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-25-listen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-25-listen/</guid>
      <description>Learn to shut up. It&amp;rsquo;s easier said than done. Especially if you grew up to speak what&amp;rsquo;s on your mind. However, we weren&amp;rsquo;t taught how to listen - like properly listen to a person, surrounding, a video, and even thoughts. There are so many things in this life that you can learn if you just sit, focus, and listen carefully. Listen. You can talk when it&amp;rsquo;s the right time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfect</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-24-perfect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-24-perfect/</guid>
      <description>There is no such thing as perfect. You&amp;rsquo;ll just have to chase what&amp;rsquo;s going to be perfect for you. You will feel constant disappointment time and time again. Once you&amp;rsquo;re in that treadmill of chasing perfection, you just keep getting hungry the further you go. Perfection is an enemy that most of us face when we&amp;rsquo;re trying to do creative work like writing, coding, speaking, and art work. However, don&amp;rsquo;t settle to mediocre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleep</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-23-focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-23-focus/</guid>
      <description>Focus is very important. This is what sets a task to be done in months or days into hours and minutes. Having focus means having the dexterity to know where to shoot your arrow. For me to be in focus, I need to be in flow. I was a victim of being a &amp;ldquo;hardworker&amp;rdquo; in the past, where I burn the midnight oil to non-valuable things.
I need to make sure I setup my mindset and environment to respect my thought processing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing MacOS Apps using .NET</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/developing-macos-apps-using-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 02:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/developing-macos-apps-using-net/</guid>
      <description>The .NET framework (and the wider ecosystem) has embraced a lot of openness these past few years. Gone are the days when .NET only works on Windows. However, as the journey to &amp;ldquo;One .NET&amp;rdquo; is still unfolding, there is a lot of confusion on how we can use .NET on MacOS. There is Mono, .NET Core, .NET 5, Xamarin.Mac, Xamarin.Forms, Mac Catalyst, .NET 6, and MAUI. This blog post explains some of the core concepts across these nomenclature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleep</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-22-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-22-sleep/</guid>
      <description>Sleep is very important for the obvious health reasons. What I also found out is that having a good sleep allows me to be a creative thinker when I have to think of new ideas. I do have a habit of staying up late if I need or want to finish something. If the means to do it is already defined, such as programming a module with clear business requirements - all I need is the time, focus, and resources to do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Message to the young</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/message-to-the-young/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 16:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/message-to-the-young/</guid>
      <description>I recently gave a graduation speech to my high school alma matter. Compared to my usual technical talks, this time it&amp;rsquo;s about inspiring the younger generation and to share some of the key lessons and experiences I&amp;rsquo;ve had for over 12 years since I graduated. This is also a good reflection of what I will advise my younger self if I am talking to him right now.
Below, I summarize my speech that is in a written medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deadlines</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-21-deadlines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-21-deadlines/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes I don&amp;rsquo;t believe that there is such thing as a &amp;ldquo;deadline&amp;rdquo; or end of life for a project. You just define what you want to build given the time, resources, and talent that is available for you. A deadline could probably be re-word as a milestone or a target, in which there is a certain state that you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a product to be developed. Deadlines are stressful, I want to avoid that word.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binaural Beats</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-20-binaural-beats/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-20-binaural-beats/</guid>
      <description>[[Binaural Beats]] is a type of music that really works for me. It helps me stay relaxed, calm, and focused. This is my go to playlist when I need to work at night. This is particularly useful if I already know what I need to do, and I just need the right set of mindset to execute them. I would recommend it to anyone who is looking for a go to music while doing creative or logical work such as programming or writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieving Success</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-19-achieving-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-19-achieving-success/</guid>
      <description>Achieving &amp;ldquo;success&amp;rdquo; is actually very simple, but the process is often hard. For example, you want to be an author, all you have to do is to keep on writing - over and over, day in and out. You won&amp;rsquo;t be an author &amp;ldquo;overnight&amp;rdquo; per-se, it&amp;rsquo;s those thousands and millions of words that come out of your mind and the hundreds of revisions that will make you an author.
The same applies to being an entrepreneur, all you have to do is to keep on exploring business opportunities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is success?</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-18-what-is-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-18-what-is-success/</guid>
      <description>What is success? Spoiler alert: It&amp;rsquo;s relative. What it means is that success would mean differently to each and every individual. Other would consider having a lot of money as successful. For some, it&amp;rsquo;s about having influence and fanbase. Others is about being a CEO or Director of a company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Influencers</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-17-online-influencers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-17-online-influencers/</guid>
      <description>Be careful with influencers. Most of the time, they are after their own agenda. You&amp;rsquo;re just a number in their likes, views, and subscribers.
There are dangers of being a consumer of a product - excessively. Participate when you can. Add a comment, share your insights, write about what you think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep on Writing</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-16-keep-on-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-16-keep-on-writing/</guid>
      <description>I have to keep on writing. Write what I feel. Write what I know. Start it, even if it’s just a draft. I have to keep on writing because eventually I will forget what’s on my head right now, I will forget what I’m feeling, I will forget the person living inside my body today. Write so that I can re-live each and every moment of it.
I want to write all sorts of topic, from [DeFi] and [Blockchain], to [Microsoft Azure] and [DotNet5].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with DeFi</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/getting-started-with-defi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 16:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/getting-started-with-defi/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Blockchain is not dead. Actually, quite the contrary is happening in the past year. There are more and more interest and it&amp;rsquo;s gaining a lot more traction than before. A big portion of this growth is due to &amp;ldquo;DeFi&amp;rdquo; AKA Decentralised Finance applications. From the hyped cryptocurrencies, we are now seeing the new next wave of this transformation as we see more financial products being developed: lending, exchanges, yield farming, and pools just to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feeling Nervous</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-15-feeling-nervous/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 03:56:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-15-feeling-nervous/</guid>
      <description>It’s few minutes before my talk, and I still feel a little bit nervous about it. I’ve been speaking to conferences for almost a decade now and I had all sorts of experiences with it already.
I’t okay to feel nervous, it means that you care about the event that is about to happen. It means that something alongside you values that aspect of life. Speaking is one of those things that I still get nervous time and time again, because I still care about it, I still want to improve about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Being Busy</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-14-being-busy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 03:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-14-being-busy/</guid>
      <description>Being busy does not always equate to being productive. You can just be in a state of busy because you think you&amp;rsquo;re doing something important. Sometimes, what you need is not &amp;ldquo;to be busy&amp;rdquo;, but &amp;ldquo;to be focused&amp;rdquo; on a task at hand. Time management is always the key to ensure that you get the right things done in your glorified to do list. Next time, instead of saying &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m busy&amp;rdquo;, say something like &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll be working on&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;I have an urgent thing to finish, I&amp;rsquo;ll be right back to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Ultimate Windows and Mac Setup (2021 Edition)</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/my-ultimate-windows-and-mac-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 16:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/my-ultimate-windows-and-mac-setup/</guid>
      <description>Introduction My Battle Station @ 2021
In a parallel world, I&amp;rsquo;ll be just using 1 device and 1 Operating system for all the things. However, given the nature of my work with mobile, web, blockchain, machine learning, and cloud development, I need to have multiple devices to cater things.
I tried doing &amp;ldquo;Shared mouse and keyboard&amp;rdquo; in the past such as Synergy, but I decided to use a KVM switch instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boredom</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-13-boredom/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 02:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/mlogs/2021-07-13-boredom/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s okay to be bored from time to time. It means that you don&amp;rsquo;t have something that is urgent and important. It&amp;rsquo;s bad to be bored if it&amp;rsquo;s a coping mechanism to avoid stress. A right amount of stress is good for you, to keep you challenged and energised - also in a way have purpose in life. Aim to have boring days, so that out of the stressful day, you have some time to recharge and contemplate on what&amp;rsquo;s really important for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH Connect to Linux Server from a Mac using SOCKS5 Proxy</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/ssh-connect-to-linux-server-from-a-mac-using-socks5-proxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 16:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/ssh-connect-to-linux-server-from-a-mac-using-socks5-proxy/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending a lot of time lately in setting up on-premises Linux Servers. There are a lot of reasons why you would like to SSH to a Linux server such as checking configuration files, copying files, or even port forwarding.
Just open your MacOS terminal and the command to ssh to a Linux Server is as simple as:
ssh user@host or ssh michael@192.0.0.1
However, where it gets tricky is when you need to use a proxy such as SOCKS5 in order to access that Linux server from your MacOS machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to disable auto-locking of MacOS Keychains</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/how-to-disable-auto-locking-of-macos-keychains/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 23:27:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/how-to-disable-auto-locking-of-macos-keychains/</guid>
      <description>Signing an iOS app for release is one of the trivial things most mobile developers face. A lot of CLIs and SAAS emerged as part of this struggle. However, not all companies have adopted to those tools and they still prefer to build their apps in their on-prem data servers. They use something like TeamCity or Azure DevOps Server.
We streamlined the configuration of our Mac Build agents to a repository where we can update our Provisioning Profiles, Keychains, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 3 Types of Blockchain and Cryptocurrencies people I’ve met</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/the-3-types-of-blockchain-and-cryptocurrencies-people-ive-met/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 03:28:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/the-3-types-of-blockchain-and-cryptocurrencies-people-ive-met/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been in the crazy Blockchain space for quite a while now. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of conversations and people I&amp;rsquo;ve met online and in-person to talk about it. Over and over, I see patterns on the people I interact with whether they do it as part of their job, an enthusiast, developer, investor, or simply just a person.
I&amp;rsquo;ve probably had hundreds of interactions already and most likely, they will belong to either of these 3 buckets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I don’t read or watch mainstream media that much</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/why-i-dont-read-or-watch-mainstream-media-that-much/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 05:45:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/why-i-dont-read-or-watch-mainstream-media-that-much/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I was a kid, I was never really the person who watches the mainstream television to watch news. Watching news on a television is a culture that a lot of people just grew up with as a &amp;ldquo;default.&amp;rdquo;
Here are some of thoughts on why I don&amp;rsquo;t value reading or watching mainstream media anymore.
 The important news will come to you one way or the other. They are written or crafted to trigger emotions rather than inform about things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why you should experience being self-employed</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/why-you-should-experience-being-self-employed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 21:18:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/why-you-should-experience-being-self-employed/</guid>
      <description>In someone&amp;rsquo;s employment life, she/he dreams of having her/his own company to beat the thoughts of having a manager or a boss. You know the promise of being your own boss, handling your own time, and $$$ - who wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want that? It&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;relatively&amp;rdquo; easy to establish a company compare to the last decades - thanks to technology. There are also a lot of avenues to profit from &amp;ldquo;the gig economy&amp;rdquo; that sometimes get big and would need a team to work on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to beat procrastination</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/how-to-beat-procrastination/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:47:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/how-to-beat-procrastination/</guid>
      <description>One of the colossal beasts that all knowledge workers fight time and time again is procrastination. This is when you know you should work, but you don&amp;rsquo;t have enough willpower to do it. You can&amp;rsquo;t code, you can&amp;rsquo;t do that design document, you can&amp;rsquo;t write that next blog post&amp;hellip; the list goes on. Here are 5 of my usual methods when I&amp;rsquo;m stuck in that limbo.
Avoid Distractions The first and obvious thing that you have to do is to avoid distraction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You should read books, you know you should</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/you-should-read-books-you-know-you-should/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 20:47:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/you-should-read-books-you-know-you-should/</guid>
      <description>Before 2018, I was never a book reader. Reading a book seems like a chore to me. I can barely finish a chapter. I always had that internal conflict (possibly based from childhood experience) that only &amp;ldquo;the smart people&amp;rdquo; can read books. Another factor is, I&amp;rsquo;ve always associated books to &amp;ldquo;school&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;academia&amp;rdquo; that felt like an enclosed culture that didn&amp;rsquo;t really synced in to me. Also, I&amp;rsquo;d rather watch a film or TV series than read a 300 to 500 pager book - because of cinematics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI across the Microsoft Cloud</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/ai-across-the-microsoft-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 09:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/ai-across-the-microsoft-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Machine Learning (ML) are trending topics right now. In 2021, there are countless of ways to have a form of &amp;ldquo;AI&amp;rdquo; in your apps and platforms. A lot of companies from startups to software giants offer services that relate to this space. I spent the last 2 years exploring this space, and I still swimming my way as the movements in this area are quick and it&amp;rsquo;s hard to keep up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why it’s okay to be “an ordinary” developer</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/why-its-okay-to-be-an-ordinary-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 19:22:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/why-its-okay-to-be-an-ordinary-developer/</guid>
      <description>Someone once asked me, what does it take to become a prominent developer? A 10X Engineer? You know some who are &amp;ldquo;extraordinary&amp;rdquo;. What do you mean by extraordinary? I&amp;rsquo;ve always had some thoughts (all of us do) around it, but my understanding and opinion of it is now much more concrete. Actually, this applies not only to being a developer, but to any other career or profession that you&amp;rsquo;re in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Intentionalization: Don’t click that next button</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/digital-intentionalization-dont-click-that-next-button/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 22:29:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/digital-intentionalization-dont-click-that-next-button/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s very tempting to click on &amp;ldquo;that next button&amp;rdquo; wether that is from YouTube, Netflix, Facebook videos or any endless buffet of consumption. You start watching a video about a topic you&amp;rsquo;re really interested in to and end up watching something weird after 3 hours. As I do more research in my personal journey of Digital Intentionalization, this is probably one of the most obvious ones. We let the platform play the next content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My only goal for 2021: Digital Intentionality</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/my-only-goal-for-2021-digital-intentionality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2021 23:15:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/my-only-goal-for-2021-digital-intentionality/</guid>
      <description>During the holidays, I was contemplating on what skills should I invest time on for 2021. As someone who is working in the technology field, there are a lot of exciting things to double-down on: from Artificial Intelligence (AI), Internet of Things (IoT), Blockchain, and a plethora of technology trends. As I reflected on how my 2020 went in terms of career and lifestyle, I noticed that there is an area I really need to work on - my digital life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Synology NAS Series – Cloud Sync with Azure Storage</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/synology-nas-series-cloud-sync-with-azure-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 03:55:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/synology-nas-series-cloud-sync-with-azure-storage/</guid>
      <description>Foreword Synology reached out to me to give their new DiskStation DS920+a review. If you&amp;rsquo;re not yet aware of Synology, they are the leading NAS (Network-attached storage) provider for home and work use-cases. You can use a NAS for pretty much anything such as backing up files, sharing files in a local network, streaming media files, or have your own &amp;ldquo;private cloud&amp;rdquo;.
Throughout the years, the concept of NAS has developed and there is now a very thin line between doing things locally in your network and storage capabilities of cloud vendors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Years of being a Microsoft MVP!</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/5-years-of-being-a-microsoft-mvp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 07:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/5-years-of-being-a-microsoft-mvp/</guid>
      <description>Wow! It’s been 5 years since my first Microsoft MVP award. If you don’t know what the Microsoft MVP program is, check this site. Throughout the years, I have transitioned from various categories and technology award. In particular, Windows Development (Windows 8/8.1/10/RT and XAML), to Developer Technologies (C#, .NET, Xamarin), to Azure with focus on Blockchain, PAAS (Platform as a Service), and Integrations.
In those years, I’ve seen Microsoft and the MVP program changed a lot (for the better).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I’m going to start writing again!</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/writing-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 07:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/blog/writing-again/</guid>
      <description>I have been meaning to write a blog post for an awfully long time, but it has blocked me for so many reasons. There are many reasons I stopped writing. I find different excuses for not doing it. Lazy. Busy. Afraid that contents I write may not be good enough. I feel my English is not good enough. So much more. No one will read it, why write?
But then the more I think about it, the more I realised that I spend a lot of time in my day writing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>👨🏻‍💻 About Me</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 04:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello there 👋 Welcome to my little space of the internet that I can call mine.
For the past 10 years, I’ve spent my career dealing with software and the cloud. I wore many hats from being a developer, tester, data engineer, IT operations, solutions architect, project manager, technical pre-sales, trainer, and everything else in between. I had some very successful outcomes and some that also failed or did not materialised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>👨🏻‍💻 About Me</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 04:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/presentations/</guid>
      <description>Hello there 👋 Welcome to my little space of the internet that I can call mine.
For the past 10 years, I’ve spent my career dealing with software and the cloud. I wore many hats from being a developer, tester, data engineer, IT operations, solutions architect, project manager, technical pre-sales, trainer, and everything else in between. I had some very successful outcomes and some that also failed or did not materialised.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>👨🏻‍💻 About Me</title>
      <link>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 04:01:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.michaeljohnpena.com/projects/</guid>
      <description>Hello there 👋 Welcome to my little space of the internet that I can call mine.
For the past 10 years, I’ve spent my career dealing with software and the cloud. I wore many hats from being a developer, tester, data engineer, IT operations, solutions architect, project manager, technical pre-sales, trainer, and everything else in between. I had some very successful outcomes and some that also failed or did not materialised.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
